Hey, hey. What's up, my friend?
Happy New Year. Yeah, I know it's a few
days past the new year, but still
wishing you a happy new year. And this
period is where most trading gurus
disappear faster than David Copperfield
when asked about their past year trading
results. So, here's my trading results
for 2025. So, for the first trading
account that I have, this account adopts
a momentum trading strategy. It's up
about 45 46% for the year. And I have
another trading account. This account,
it's up about 20% for the year as you
can see over here. And this is the
year-to- date returns. And for those of
you who use interactive broker, you
know, this is a very familiar looking
chart looking equity curve. Yeah. So,
these are the two main accounts that I
have adopting a momentum and a mean
reversion trading strategies. And if you
want to learn more about momentum and
mean reversion trading, I actually have
a free 54minut training over here that
walks you through this trading different
trading strategies including the trading
rules backtest data the full system and
whatnot. So if you want to grab bit just
go down to tradingwithra.com/go
or I'll put the link somewhere below
this video and you can access it. Now
moving on, I want to share with you four
takeaways that I had in 2025. And these
takeaways are important because if you
implement them, if you adopt them,
right, you will see your trading jump to
the next level because that's what it
has done for my trading. I wish these
are the lessons that I had learned
earlier. So these are my four big
takeaways for 2025 which kind of
reinforce my beliefs, right, about the
market.
Number one, more markets, more
opportunities. So why do I say this is
that I actively trade stocks. I trade
many stocks in the US stock market. But
can you guess in 2025 which is the
market that gave me the biggest profit?
Take a guess. Let me tell you the market
is
gold. Why gold? Okay, so have a look at
this chart. So if you look at gold, the
chart of gold, this by the way is the
weekly time frame. This is one of the
best trending market in 2024 and 2025.
And I actually went long in around here.
I think this was June 2024. And I write
this move up higher. And currently I'm
still holding gold. And the reason why
I'm sharing this with you is when you
trade more markets, you have more
opportunities. Your trading setups have
more markets to be exposed to. And this
increases your odds of capturing a
profit riding a trend. Especially if you
are have using a momentum or trend
following approach. So it's like dating,
right? If you only hang out at, you
know, one coffee shop, you'll never meet
anyone new. But if you hang out at
different coffee shops, hawker centers,
restaurants, you'll probably, you know,
find a lot more dating potential or
different women out there. So hang out
around different places, right? Uh for
those of you who are single and don't
tell my wife I said that. So coming
2026, I plan to trade even more markets.
plan to go into the crypto markets and
develop trading strategies and systems
for that market as well. So if for those
of you who only trade one market like
forex, stocks, my suggestion, something
to consider is know expand your market
universe and you know see where you
could find more trading opportunities.
Number two, the holy grail of trading.
So this is something that I have
repeated a number of times but this this
year 202 I mean last year 2025 it really
reinforces this principle. So what is
the holy grail of trading? So if you
look at this table over here, it's two
trading systems. One is a STF sense for
systematic trend following and the other
one is MRT not the train in Singapore
but mean reversion trading. And you can
see that each of these trading system
they all have losing year like 2020 209
2018 2012 trend following had losing
years even in 2023. Same for mean
reversion trading here and here. So how
can you reduce your number of losing
years such that you can profit almost
every single year whether it's a bull or
bare market and the answer is pretty
simple. You want to combine, you want to
trade multiple trading systems because
when you do that, look at this over
here. Look at this column over here. You
will pretty much improve your risk
adjusted returns. You can see the final
column over here. When you allocate
let's say 50% to trend following, 50% to
mean reversion trading, you get results
like this where almost every single year
you are making a profit. So that's the
power that's the beauty of trading
multiple trading strategies. And because
of this principle during the April of
2025 where Trump implement you know the
tariffs the stock market kind of like
pullback crash I also suffered losses
but my losses are nowhere as deep as the
S&P 500 because I have multiple trading
systems right that are running and some
of them actually do well during a market
correction or a market pullback. So
that's the power of having multiple
trading systems, right? It's kind of
like, you know, having multiple multiple
kids. Even if one kid disappoint you,
guess what? You still have a few more
backup here. [laughter and gasps] Okay.
So, so next one, number three. If you
fail to plan, you plan to fail. So this
is sounds very cliche, but this really
helped me sleep peacefully for the whole
of 2025. At least I, you know, don't
wake up panicking, sweating buckets,
right, in the middle of the night
because of the financial markets. So why
do I say that? So if you recall around
April 2025,
it was where Trump started, you know,
pushing out a lot of the tariffs, you
know, you know, ter tarifying tariffing
all the different countries in the
world, you know, China, uh, Russia, all
the different countries, India and
whatnot. And I thought really that
during that period things can get a lot
worse. I was thinking, man, the market
could possibly, you know, correct 30,
40%, never know. So I was prepared at
that point in time to do a few things.
number one witness my portfolio possibly
erasing 30% of its value. I was already
visualizing that to happen, right?
Because even if I were to follow the
rules of my trading system, it could go
into a draw down, maybe a draw down of
30%. So in my mind, I'm already
picturing visualizing that I'm really
losing that amount of money. First thing
number two, I am also prepared for my
systems to move in cash. So you know
once it enters a draw down and starts,
you know, cutting losses, it will move
to cash because the market is bearish.
number of my systems will move to cash.
And number three, when you move to cash,
I know that it's a great opportunity to
invest in solid companies for cheap. So,
I was prepared. I already highlighted my
levels. If the price comes to those
level, I want to buy these quality
companies. And guess what? None of it
materialized as the market shortly after
after that broke up to new all-time
high.
Still that the planning has been
invaluable to me because I know that no
matter what happens even if the market
is bullish or it's bearish or it goes
into a crisis recession I know what I'm
going to do every step of the way of the
way visually visually in my mind I've
already visualized the potential loss
I'm going to incur. So this way during
these difficult times I can still
execute the rules of my trading system
and that's how important it was for me
during this period. So a key reminder is
that when the times are good, prepare
for the downside and when times are bad,
grab the opportunity that you have
planned for. Number four, everything can
be figured out. So here's the thing,
right? The dream of every trader is to
automate their trading, right? So then
that's where your trading algorithm,
your system, you know, it's like a ATM
that prints money on demand. That's like
every trader's dream. So it's my goal
for many years to automate fully
automate my training. So I don't have to
you know click a single button and by
the way the results that I've shared
with you that you've seen earlier for a
good 6 months I didn't click a single
button to get those results because you
know it has been fully automated and let
me explain to you how how that happened.
So my goal was to all along automate my
trading but the feedback that I've been
getting from developers from other quan
traders that I spoke to is that you know
it's too difficult right now you know it
cannot be done right using the the tools
that you're using or I hear things like
it will take you too much time and
resources it's not worth the effort and
money that you have to spend so one year
ago my friend introduced to me this
programmer so thanks Elvin if you're
watching this video so he introduced to
me this programmer to help me automate
my trading without lifting a finger and
what the programmer did right is is
amazing. All right, it helps me to
automatically trade my systems,
calculate the position size, manage my
risk, submit the orders, everything from
start to finish. And it's a very big
project. But how did the programmer
approach it? Very simple. Every
thing, the entire big goal is broken
down into a step-by-step process. And
once you break it out into a
step-by-step process, what's then left
to do is to actually link up each
individual small step together. And when
you piece everything together, the goal
is completed. It's kind of like, you
know, teaching your kids to go, hey, you
know, Raina, go and clean clean up your
room. You tell that to your kids,
they're not going to clean up the room
because there is no step-by-step
process. Instead, you want to tell them,
you know, to pick up the toys, put the
clothes in the drawer, stop hiding your
food under your bed, you know, give them
specific instructions and then they when
they do it, they will eventually clean
up their room. It's the same for this uh
trading automation that I did is one big
goal which is automate it break it down
into you know series of 20 30 40 steps
and then from those steps link it up all
together and that's how the automation
is uh successful and it worked right my
dream did become a reality. So
that's again a very big thing for me in
2025. And finally, uh before you move
on, if you want to grab my free training
where you'll learn proven trading
strategies that work, right, that are
backed by data, you can go down to my
website over here, tradingwithra.com/go.
I'll put the link below this video. You
can get this free training with I'll
teach you a mean reversion trading
system, a momentum and a trend following
system. So with that said, I wish you
good luck, good trading, great speaking
with you once again and talk to you
soon.